#大家好 前兩天我們去了趟四川
Hi everyone. We went to Sichuan a couple of days ago.
#你看 我們的手沒有這麼快
Look! We don't have the agile hands.
#兄弟過來把攝影小哥的樹都缷了
Our buddies have already come to clear the trees at Mr. Cameraman's home.
#大部份都被它[SIC]拿走啦 就還有一點點
Almost all have already been picked, just a little bit remains.
#我們去看一下有沒有
Let's see if there is still any.
#兩個籮筐都不知道能不能裝得滿啊
I wonder if we can fill up the two baskets.
#這邊這顆[SIC]樹還有
There are still some on this tree here.
#那邊 那邊那顆[SIC]樹沒有啦
But there are none on that, that tree over there
#剛好帶我(弟)來過幫忙
I'm taking my younger brother to assist me.
#搞點回去
We'll take some back home.
#你看 這 這顆[SIC]小樹啦
Look! This, this is a small tree.
#那兩顆[SIC]大樹都沒有 沒有板栗啦
There are no, no more chestnuts on those two larger trees.
#我們爬這顆[SIC]小樹
We're climbing this small three.
#不會掉
They're not falling down.
#哈哈哈
Ha ha ha
#差一點
Almost there.
#可以
Alright!
#你看 上樹上隨便打了一下
Look! I've just knocked several times in the tree,
#就打了那麼一點點 (註︰沒看懂，究竟他覺得多還是少？)
and there's just a little bit.
#那裡一顆[SIC]樹
The tree over there,
#還沒被人家打過的
has never been knocked.
#我去打
I'll be the first one.
#這個籮筐放在這裡
I'll leave this basket here,
#我們拿這個空籮筐過去
and go there with the empty basket.
#你看 這顆[SIC]樹 好大呀
Look! This tree, is huge!
#我上去
I'm going up.
#哎呀 好多哦
Ayo! A lot!
#就搞了那麼一點點
We've just gotten a little bit here.
#這個太小啦
This is too small.
#不好搞 不要這個
No good. I don't want it.
#大的都被兄弟摘完啦
My buddy has taken all the large ones.
#來的太晚啦
We're too late.
#我們今天準備回去啦
Let's get ready to go back home,
#就那麼一點點
with just this little bit.
#沒精神啊 搞那麼一點
I'm tired. It's already enough,
#牛皮袋又帶了那麼多
though we're coming with so many bags.
#搞了一下午
We've spent the whole good afternoon,
#就搞了那麼一點點
to have just a little bit here.
#剛好那個攀蒲
The "panpu" (pumpkins) are right here.
#幫攝影小哥 幫他拿回去
Let me help Mr Cameraman, help to bring them back home.
#這個攀蒲很多的
There're a lot of them.
#剛好把那個麵包車開過來啦
I've just driven the minivan here.
#拿刀來
Give me the knife!
#看到攀蒲就砍
I'll chop whenever and wherever I see a "panpu".
#哇 這個
Wa! This,
#這個攀蒲
this "panpu"
#那個小豬很喜歡吃的
is the piglets' favourite.
#啊 來看一下 還有沒有
Ah! Come! See if there's still any.
#你看 這個攀蒲 產量好高啊 你看
Look! The "panpu". The yield is really high, look!
#一二三四五 光這裡就五個
One two three four five. There're already five just here.
#那裡又有 那裡又有
There too, there too.
#哇 我種的怎麼不會長的
Wa! Why aren't my "panpu" growing at all?
#攝影小哥奶奶種的
But Mr. Cameraman's grandma grew them.
#哇 那麼大喔
Wa! It's huge!
#全部都砍掉
Chop them all off!
#這個黃啦 已經熟了
It turns brown. It can be eaten.
#再不搞掉的話都會爛掉的
It would start to rot if we don't chop it out.
#你看這一個
Have a look at this one.
#光這裡就有五個
There're already five right here.
#還有
But that's not all
#這裡有一個
Here's another one.
#你看 這裡有一個
Look! Here's one.
#這個是最大的這個
This is the largest, this "pampu".
#誒呦
Ayo!
#哇 這個是
Wa! This is,
#最少有三四十斤 四五十斤
it's at least 20kg, 25kg.
#好啦 幫攝影小哥
Alright. We'll bring all these back
#搬回去
for Mr. Cameraman.
#今天的視頻就到這裡啦
The video ends here.
#攝影小哥最懶
Mr. Cameraman is always the laziest.